Introducing Flexbox.
تعرّف إلى «فليكس بوكس».
Now it's when I think we're entering
أعتقد أننا ننتقل هنا
the intermediate skill level range of our work together.
إلى مستوى متوسط من المهارات.
Flexbox, the flexible box module,
«فليكس بوكس» أو وحدة الصناديق المرنة
but everyone pretty much just called Flexbox specializes in
يُعنى «فليكس بوكس» كما يُسميه الجميع
aligning and distributing elements within a parent element.
بمحاذاة وتوزيع العناصر ضمن عنصر رئيسي.
Alignment and justification can be made
يمكن أن تصبح المحاذاة والضبط
pretty easy with software such as Adobe Illustrator.
سهلة للغاية باستخدام برمجيات مثل أدوبي إلستريتر.
But until Flexbox, it was relatively difficult to distribute and
ولكن قبل «فليكس بوكس»، كان من الصعب نسبيًا توزيع
align elements in a visually appealing way with just code.
ومحاذاة العناصر بشكل جميل وجذاب باستخدام البرمجية فقط.
Flexbox comes around and brings a few things with it.
يقدم «فليكس بوكس» بعض المزايا
A flex container can expand to fit the items available inside of it.
مثل حاوية مرنة تتمدد بما يتلاءم مع العناصر بداخلها
A flex container unlike other CSS properties
بخلاف خصائص CSS الأخرى، فإن الحاوية المرنة
uses the main container with items then nested inside of it,
تستخدم الحاوية الرئيسية ثم تستقر العناصر فيها لاحقًا،
and some of the CSS properties are used only for the parent and others on the items.
وتستعمل بعض خصائص CSS فقط للعنصر الأصل فيما تستعمل البقية للعناصر الفرعية.
The terminology we will be using is container for
المصطلحات التي سنستخدمها هي الحاوية
the parent element and items for the elements inside of it.
للعنصر الأصل، والعناصر الفرعية للعناصر بداخله.
You think flex it's actually super easy.
استخدام «فليكس» في غاية السهولة.
We just set the display property of an element to
ما علينا سوى ضبط خاصية العرض display لعنصر ما
flex and you can start using all the associated keywords.
على Flex لنتمكن من استخدام جميع الكلمات المفتاحية المرتبطة به.
Let's take a look at some examples.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
لنأخذ بعض الأمثلة.